wilddogdesigns.com 2017-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Our House Rules | Etsy

At Etsy, we care deeply about privacy. We believe in transparency, and we’re committed to being upfront about our privacy practices, including how we treat your personal information. We know you care about your privacy too, so we provide settings that allow you to choose how certain information is used by Etsy. This policy explains our privacy practices for Etsy.com and EtsyStudio.com (we’ll refer to Etsy.com and EtsyStudio.com collectively as the "Site"), Etsy’s mobile applications (the "Apps"), Pattern by Etsy, Etsy Payments, and our other services provided by Etsy, Inc. or Etsy Ireland UC (collectively, "Etsy"). We'll refer to the Site, the Apps, Pattern by Etsy, Etsy Payments, and our other services as the "Services." If you are located outside of North America and South America, Etsy Ireland UC is the data controller and is responsible for your personal information.

1\. Highlights  
2\. Information Collected or Received  
3\. Choice & Control  
4\. Findability  
5\. Messages from Etsy  
6\. Community  
7\. Information Uses, Sharing, & Disclosure  
8\. Data Transfers  
9\. Legitimate Interests  
10\. Security  
11\. Data Retention  
12\. Your Rights  
13\. Withdrawing Consent  
14\. Privacy Policy Changes  
15\. Contact Etsy

We need to process your personal data to run our business and provide you with the Services. By accepting our [Terms of Use](https://www.etsy.com/legal/terms), you are confirming that you have read this policy and consent to us using your information in the ways we describe. If you don’t want us to collect or process your personal information in the ways described in this policy, you shouldn’t use the Services. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of any of our members, websites hosted through Pattern by Etsy, third-party websites, or third-party apps.

Etsy’s [Terms of Use](https://www.etsy.com/legal/terms) require all account owners or account managers to be at least 18 years of age. Those under 18 years of age and at least 13 years of age are permitted to use accounts only if the accounts are managed by someone over 18, and only if they comply with our policies relating to minors on Etsy set out in our Help article [here](https://www.etsy.com/ie/help/article/127). That Help article discusses use of the Services by minors. Children under age 13 are not permitted to use Etsy or the Services.

By using the Services, you authorize Etsy to use your information in the United States, Ireland and any other country where Etsy operates. Please be aware that the privacy laws and standards in certain countries, including the rights of authorities to access your personal information, may differ from those that apply in the country in which you reside. We will transfer personal data only to these countries to which we are permitted by law to transfer personal information, and we will take steps to ensure that your personal information continues to enjoy appropriate protections. Please see our full Privacy Policy below to learn more about how we protect personal information that’s transferred outside of Europe.

* * *

## 1\. Highlights

This section sets out a few highlights of our Privacy Policy. You can read Etsy’s full Privacy Policy below.

### Information Collected or Received

To use the Services, you will need to provide a valid email address. Depending on the Services that you choose to use, we may collect additional information, for example: information in private channels like Conversations, billing or payment information, a telephone number, and a physical address. Please note that for security and performance reasons, such content may need to be accessed by certain Etsy personnel from time to time.

We may also collect information about your use of the Services for advertising, analytics, to serve content and to protect the Services, including your IP address, browser information (including referrers), device information (such as iOS IDFA, IDFV for limited non-advertising purposes, Android AAID, and, when enabled by you, coarse and fine geographical information provided by your device).

The name associated with your Etsy account is publicly displayed and connected to your Etsy activity. You may review and change that name through your account settings. Other people may see the date you joined; ratings, reviews and related photos for items you purchased or sold; your profile information; items you listed for sale; your shop pages and policies; your Favorites, followers and those you follow; sold item listings and the number of items sold; and comments you post in our community spaces. You may optionally choose to provide and publicly display your full name and other personal information (such as birthday, gender, and location).

You may connect to the Services with an external application, in which case Etsy may receive information from that other service, as explained below.

We use technologies such as cookies, clear gifs, and log files for several purposes, including to help understand how you interact with the Site and the Services, in order to provide a better experience, and for marketing and advertising. The Apps may include third-party mobile analytics services used for similar purposes. For more information about cookies, mobile analytics, and similar technologies, see our [Cookies & Tracking Technologies page](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/3293).

Etsy and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the Services, track users’ movements around the Site, including across devices, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on the Site or through the Services. See our [Cookies & Tracking Technologies page](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/3293).

### Uses and Sharing

We use the information that we gather from you users in a number of ways. For example, if you purchase an item, we’ll share your shipping information with the seller; we could use your forum suggestions to improve the Services; we use data analytics and work with certain third-party service providers to ensure site functionality, to improve the Services, and for targeted online and offline advertising and marketing; and of course, we use your email address to communicate with you. We also partner with service providers and other third parties that collect, use, promote, and analyze information about Etsy and Etsy Studio members and visitors.

Etsy will not sell or disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent, except as specified in our Privacy Policy.

### Choices

You may review and change your information in your account settings, and you may remove certain optional pieces of information. You may also control the receipt of certain types of communications from Etsy in your account settings. We partner with third parties to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. 

Although Etsy does not currently respond to “do not track” browser headers, you may opt out of online behavioral ads provided by third-party partners through this link: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or via the Network Advertising Initiative at [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). You also may limit certain tracking by disabling cookies in your web browser. For more information about managing cookies, see our [Cookies & Tracking Technologies page](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/3293).

You may also opt out of interest-based advertising on an iOS or Android device by selecting the “Limit Ad Tracking” option in the settings of iOS or Android-based devices. Note that this does not prevent you from seeing advertisements, but limits use of device-advertising identifiers to personalize ads to your interests.

### Information

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

As described below, we’ll communicate when we make changes to our Privacy Policy.

* * *

## **ETSY PRIVACY POLICY**

## 2\. Information Collected or Received

In order to use the Services, you need to provide us with a valid email address, and for Services that require registration, a name associated with your account that you can choose and that represents your identity on Etsy. You may review and change that name through your account settings. You need to provide this information to enable us to provide you with the Services. Depending on which services you choose to use, additional information, such as a shop name, billing and payment information (including billing address, telephone number, credit card information), a telephone number, and/or a physical postal address, may be necessary in order for us to provide a particular service. You are not required to provide us with this information to sign up, but we will need it to provide certain services. For example, we need a physical postal address if you are buying something on the Site for delivery. As an Etsy seller, if you choose to use our payment service ("Etsy Payments"), Etsy may require information such as your social security number, identification ID or tax ID, date of birth, bank account information, credit card information, and/or other proof of identification in order to verify your identity and provide this service to you and to comply with applicable law. We may need to store credit card information (or arrange for it to be stored) and use it for both billing and payment purposes. Etsy may contact individual shop owners confidentially to request more information about their shops or items listed through the Services, or to ensure compliance with our rules and applicable law. In order to use certain products or services on Etsy, you may be required to complete an application; information that you submit through the application processes will not be displayed publicly and will only be used internally by Etsy, unless otherwise specified.

You can choose to provide and publicly display your full name and other personal information (such as birthday, gender, location) in connection with your account and activity. If you do not want this additional information displayed publicly, you can remove it through your account settings. 

The name associated with your account, which you may review and change in your account settings, is publicly displayed and connected to your Etsy activity. Other people may see the date you joined, reviews, ratings, profile information, items listed for sale, shop pages, sold item listings, and comments in community spaces. 

Etsy automatically receives and records information from your browser or your mobile device when you visit the Site or use the Apps or use certain other Services, such as your IP address or unique device identifier, cookies and data about which pages you visit in order to allow us to operate and provide the Services. This information is stored in log files and is collected automatically. We may combine this information from your browser or your mobile device with other information that we or our partners collect about you, including across devices. This information is used to prevent fraud and to keep the Services secure, to analyze and understand how the Services work for members and visitors, and to provide advertising and a more personalized experience for members and visitors. For more information about online tracking tools and how we use them, see our [Cookies & Tracking Technologies page](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/3293) or “Information Uses, Sharing, & Disclosure” section below.

We automatically collect device-specific information when you install, access, or use the Services. This information may include information such as the hardware model, operating system information, app version, browser information, IP address, and device identifiers. When you use the Apps, you may choose to share your geo-location details with Etsy in order to use our location-based services (although you don't need to share these details). You may choose to publish your location when you sell on Etsy. We may also determine location by using other data from your device, such as precise location information from GPS, information about wireless networks or cell towers near your mobile device, information you provide in your profile, or your IP address. We may use and store information about your location to provide features and to improve and customize the Services, for example, with more relevant content, ads, and recommendations. If you have consented to share your device location details but would no longer like to continue sharing that information with us, you may revoke your consent to the sharing of that information through the settings on the Apps or on your mobile device. If you have consented to the collection of your location-based information, we use that information in order to understand, customize, and improve the Services, including for marketing and advertising. We will only share your geo-location details with third parties (like our mapping or advertising providers) in order to provide you with the Services. You may also choose to enable the Apps to access your mobile device’s camera to upload photographs to Etsy.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to understand the functionality of the Apps on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the Apps, what happens within the Apps, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the Apps were downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information that you submit within the mobile application.

Some members or visitors may choose to connect to Etsy or register an Etsy account using an external third-party application, such as Facebook, or an app developed using the Etsy application programming interface (the "API"). Etsy may receive data from those connected third-party applications. Connecting your Etsy account to third-party applications or services is optional. If you choose to connect your account to a third-party application, Etsy may receive information from that application. We may use that information as part of providing the Services to you. You can also choose to share some of your activity on Etsy on certain social media networks which are connected to your Etsy account, and you can revoke your permission anytime in your account settings.

Etsy may receive or obtain information (for example, an email address or IP address) about a person who is not yet a registered Etsy or Etsy Studio member (a “non-member”) in connection with certain Etsy features, such as when a non-member chooses to subscribe to an Etsy newsletter, a member invites a non-member to visit the Site, a member uploads non-member information using the contact uploader feature, a non-member engages in a transaction, or a member sends a gift card code to a non-member, or a non-member uses the Guest Checkout feature when making a purchase through one of the Services. Non-member information is used only for the purposes disclosed when it was submitted to Etsy or to facilitate action authorized by the non-member. A non-member can [contact Etsy Support](https://www.etsy.com/help/contact) if they do not want Etsy to retain their information.

We also collect certain information from both members and non-members who visit websites hosted by us. This information may include your IP address or unique device identifier, and cookies and data from the pages you visit. To learn more about websites hosted by us through Pattern by Etsy, see our [Pattern Policy](https://www.etsy.com/legal/policy/pattern-policy/42449288897). For more information on our use of cookies and collection of tracking information, see our [Cookies & Tracking Technologies page](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/3293) or “Information Uses, Sharing & Disclosure” section below.

## 3\. Choice & Control

We know that members of our community value having control over their own information, so Etsy gives you the choice of providing, editing or removing certain information, as well as choices about how we contact you. You may change or correct your Etsy account information through your account settings. You may also remove certain optional information that you no longer wish to be publicly visible through the Services, such as your full name.

Etsy may send you messages about the Services or your activity. Some of these messages are required, service-related messages for members (such as transactional messages or legal notices). Other messages are not required, such as newsletters. You can control which optional messages you choose to receive by changing your account settings, and you can learn more in the “Messages from Etsy” section of this policy.

If you have chosen to connect your account to an external third-party application, such as Facebook, or an app developed using the API, you can change your settings and remove permission for the app by changing your account settings.

If you no longer wish to use the Services or receive service-related messages, then you may close your account. [Click here](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/53) to learn how to close your account.

## 4\. Findability

You may choose to connect directly with your email service provider, your mobile device’s address book, or a social network account to import your contacts to Etsy. We do not retain the login information for your email service, mobile device, or social network site. You may be able to search for people you know by email address or phone number on the Site or by connecting to your mobile device’s contact list through the Apps. Finding your friends on Etsy helps you connect with them on our platform. For example, you can follow another member’s public activity, such as public Favorites. When you begin following another member’s activity, they will receive an email notification (if the member has consented to receiving this type of email). When you provide us with personal information about your contacts, we will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided. 

If you do not want your contacts to be able to find you on Etsy through your email address, phone number, or social networking connections, then you may opt out through your account settings. If you do not wish to be located on Etsy via your full name, you can remove your full name and instead may use a nickname or alias as your name in your public account information. If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at legal@etsy.com. 

## 5\. Messages from Etsy

On occasion, Etsy may need to contact you. Primarily, these messages are delivered by email or by push notifications, and every account is required to keep a valid email address on file to receive messages. Etsy may need to contact you by telephone to provide member support or for transaction-related purposes if you give us permission to call you. Additionally, and with your consent, Etsy may send you an SMS (or similar) message or physical mail in order to provide you with customer support or to provide you with information about products and features that you may find of interest. You may update your contact preferences in your account settings.

Some messages from Etsy are service-related and necessary for members and Guest Checkout users. You agree that Etsy can send you non-marketing emails or messages, such as those related to transactions, your account, security, or product changes. Examples of service-related messages include an email address confirmation/welcome email when you register your account, notification of an order, service availability, modification of key features or functions, and correspondence with Etsy’s support team. 

When you register for an account, or provide us with your email address or phone number such as for a Guest Checkout purchase or to subscribe to a newsletter, you agree to receive marketing emails and messages from us. You can unsubscribe at any time from marketing emails through the opt-out link included in marketing emails or messages. Members may also control some marketing emails or messages through their account settings as well as through the opt-out link included in marketing emails or messages. 

A contact-importer feature is available to help you locate and connect with your friends and contacts who may be members of Etsy (see the "Findability" section above for more information). If someone in your contact list is not already a member, you may invite them to join Etsy and an email will be sent to them on your behalf. Recipients of email invitations may opt out of receiving future invitations by following instructions in the email invitation message. You may send an invitation only to someone who has given you consent to receive one.

Etsy and Etsy Studio are both marketplaces and communities. We offer several features that allow members to connect and communicate in public or semi-public spaces, such as Forums and Teams. You don't have to use these features, but if you do, please use common sense and good judgment when posting in these community spaces or sharing your personal information with others through the Services. Be aware that any personal information that you choose to submit there can be read, collected, or used by others, or could be used to send unsolicited messages to you. Etsy generally does not remove content from community spaces, and your posts may remain public after your account is closed. You are responsible for the personal information that you choose to post in community spaces through the Services. 

Another Etsy or Etsy Studio member may follow your public activity on the Site to receive updates, such as when you add an item to your public Favorites. You may choose to make certain activities private through your account settings. After a member has begun following your activity, you have the option to block that member if you do not wish to share your updates with that specific person.

## 7\. Information Uses, Sharing & Disclosure

We respect your privacy. Etsy will not disclose your name, email address or other personal information to third parties without your consent, except as specified in this policy. We rely on three separate and overlapping bases to process your personal information lawfully. First, it’s necessary for us to process your personal information in certain ways in order to provide the Services to you, in accordance with a contract between you and us, namely, our [Terms of Use](https://www.etsy.com/legal/terms) (for example, giving a seller your shipping address so that they can send you the item you purchased). Second, where you have given us valid consent to use your data in certain ways, we will rely on your consent. Third, as described in more detail below in the section titled “Legitimate Interests”, in certain cases we may process your information where necessary to further Etsy's legitimate interests, where those legitimate interests are not overridden by your rights or interests. 

We use your information to provide and improve the Services and our products, for billing and payments, for identification and authentication, for targeted online and offline marketing, to contact members or interested parties, and for general research and aggregate reporting. For example, in accordance with our existing [case resolution process](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/364), we may use information you provide to resolve disputes with Etsy or other members. We may learn the sorts of products that you’re interested in from your browsing and purchasing behavior on (and off) the Site or Apps and suggest potential purchases as a result. Similarly, we or our sellers may advertise our Services or our sellers’ products through a variety of different mediums. As part of this, we may work with advertising partners such as Facebook or Google.

As part of the buying and selling process, Etsy will facilitate the sharing of information between the two members involved in the transaction, such as the other Etsy or Etsy Studio member's email address, shipping address, and payment information. By making a sale or a purchase on Etsy or Etsy Studio, you are directing us to share your information in this way. We expect you to respect the privacy of the member whose information you have received. As described in Etsy's [Terms of Use](https://www.etsy.com/legal/terms), you have a limited license to use that information only for Etsy or or Etsy Studio-related communications or for Etsy or Etsy Studio-facilitated transactions. Etsy has not granted a license to you to use the information for unsolicited commercial messages or unauthorized transactions. Without express consent from that person, you must not add any Etsy or Etsy Studio member to your email or physical mailing list or otherwise use or store any member’s personal information. Please remember that you need to comply with all relevant legal rules when you use the Services. This includes applicable data protection and privacy laws which govern the ways in which you can use another Etsy or Etsy Studio member’s information. Such laws may require that you post, and comply with, your own privacy policy, which must be accessible to Etsy members you interact with and compatible with this policy and Etsy’s [Terms of Use](https://www.etsy.com/legal/terms). 

Etsy may release your personal information to a third party in the following limited circumstances: in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet legitimate national security or law enforcement requirements; to protect, establish, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, including to collect a debt; to comply with a subpoena, court order, legal process, or other legal requirement; or when we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, threats to our property, or violations of Etsy's [Terms of Use](https://www.etsy.com/legal/terms). 

If Etsy receives a lawful, verified request for a member’s records or information in one of the limited circumstances described in the previous paragraph, Etsy may disclose personal information, which may include, but may not be limited to, a member’s name, address, phone number, email address, and company name. Find out more about how Etsy responds to requests for records or information about members of Etsy’s community in our [Requests for Information Policy](https://www.etsy.com/legal/requests-for-information) and our [Intellectual Property Policy](https://www.etsy.com/legal/ip).

Etsy is affiliated with a variety of businesses and works closely with them for a variety of purposes, including assisting us to perform and improve the Services. With your consent, these businesses may offer promotions (including email promotions) or sell items or services to you through the Services. Etsy may also provide services or sell products jointly with affiliated businesses. When an affiliated business assists in facilitating your transaction, we may need to share information related to the transaction with that affiliated business in order to facilitate your transaction. 

Etsy may share demographic information with business partners, but it will always be aggregated and de-personalized, so that personally-identifiable information is not revealed.

Etsy also needs to engage third-party companies and individuals (such as payment processors, research companies, and analytics and security providers) to help us operate and provide the Services. These third parties have only limited access to your information, may use your information only to perform these tasks on our behalf, and are obligated to Etsy not to disclose or use your information for other purposes.

In some cases, Etsy may choose to buy or sell assets. Such transactions may be necessary and in our legitimate interests. In these types of transactions (such as a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership, or transfer of all or substantially all of Etsy’s assets), member information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. If Etsy intends to transfer information about you, Etsy will notify you by email or by putting a prominent notice on the Site and the App, and you will be afforded an opportunity to opt out before information about you becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

Third-party plug-ins also may collect information about your use of the Site. For example, when you load a page on Etsy that has a social plug-in from a third-party site or service, such as a “Like” or “Send” button, you are also loading content from that third-party site. That site may request cookies directly from your browser. These interactions are subject to the privacy policy of the third-party site. In addition, certain cookies and other tracking mechanisms on the Site are used by third parties for targeted online marketing and other purposes. These technologies allow a partner to recognize your computer or mobile device each time you use the Services, but do not allow access to personal information from Etsy. Please be aware that when you use third-party sites or services, their own terms and privacy policies will govern your use of those sites or services. While Etsy provides you with access to these third-party technologies, Etsy does not have control over the actual functionality of these third-party technologies, and they are subject to that third party's privacy policy and Etsy's Privacy Policy. For more information, see our [Cookies & Tracking Technologies page](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/3293). 

We use non-technically necessary cookies and similar technologies only with your consent. If you prefer to prevent third parties from setting and accessing cookies on your computer, you may set your browser to block cookies. You may also opt out of the use of cookies by Google Analytics [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Additionally, you may remove yourself from the interest-based advertising of companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance program by opting out [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) (or, if you are located in the European Union, click [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)) and via the Network Advertising Initiative by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). Although the Site currently does not respond to “do not track” browser headers, you can limit tracking by taking these steps. On an iOS or Android device, you can restrict interest-based advertising by selecting “Limit Ad Tracking” in the iOS settings or Android settings of each respective type of device. Note that while this limits interest-based advertising, it does not prevent you from receiving advertising at all.

We can speak only for ourselves; this policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Etsy does not own or control or individuals that Etsy does not employ or manage. If you provide your information to others, different practices may apply to the use or disclosure of the information that you provide to them. Etsy does not control the privacy policies of third parties, including other Etsy or Etsy Studio members. Etsy is not responsible for the privacy or security practices of Etsy or Etsy Studio members or other websites on the Internet, even those linked to or from the Services. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others. 

## 8\. Data Transfers

Etsy operates a global service. If you reside outside of North America or South America, your information is controlled by Etsy Ireland UC. Etsy Ireland UC may share some of the information it gathers with Etsy, Inc. (its US parent company) or other Etsy affiliates for purposes described in this Privacy Policy, including for ID verification, transaction reviews, and payment processing.

The United States, European Economic Area (“EEA”) Member States, and other countries all have different laws. When your data is moved from your home country to another country, the laws and rules that protect your personal information in the country to which your information is transferred may be different from those in the country in which you live. For example, the circumstances in which law enforcement can access personal information may vary from country to country. In particular, if your data is in the US, it may be accessed by government authorities in accordance with US law.

To the extent that Etsy is deemed to transfer personal information outside of the EEA, we rely separately, alternatively, and independently on the following legal bases to transfer your information: 

### Model Clauses

The European Commission has adopted standard data protection clauses (also known as Model Clauses) which provide safeguards for personal information that is transferred outside of Europe. We often use Model Clauses when transferring personal data outside of Europe. You can request a copy of our Model Clauses by emailing legal@etsy.com.

### Necessary for the performance of the contract between Etsy and its members

Etsy is a voluntary service; you can choose whether or not you want to use the Services. However, if you want to use the Services, you need to agree to our [Terms of Use](https://www.etsy.com/legal/terms), which set out the contract between Etsy and its members. As we operate in countries worldwide (including in the US) and use technical infrastructure in the US to deliver the Services to you, in accordance with the contract between us, we need to transfer your personal information to the US and to other jurisdictions as necessary to provide the Services. Simply put, we can’t provide you with the Services without moving your data around the world.  

### Consent

When signing up to use the Services, you must consent to the transfer of your personal data abroad, including to the US and other jurisdictions, to provide you with the Services and generally to process your information in accordance with this policy. As noted above, we simply can’t provide the Services to you if you don’t consent to this.

## 9\. Legitimate Interests

Etsy relies on several legitimate interests in using and sharing your personal information.  These interests include: 

  * improving and customizing the Services for our community;
  * understanding how the Services are being used;
  * exploring and unlocking ways to develop and grow our business; 
  * obtaining insights into usage patterns of the Services;
  * ensuring the safety and security of the Services; and
  * enhancing our members’ protection against spam, harassment, IP infringement, crime, and security risks of all kind. 

## 10\. Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and after it is received. Your account information is protected by a password. It is important that you protect against unauthorized access to your account and information by choosing your password carefully and by keeping your password and computer secure, such as by signing out after using the Services. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at legal@etsy.com. 

Etsy encrypts certain information (such as credit card numbers) using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Etsy follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and after it is received. Unfortunately, no method of transmission over the internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Etsy offers optional advanced security settings for members, such as [two-factor authentication](https://www.etsy.com/help/article/3335) for signing in, full-site SSL, and login history; you can enable these options under your account settings.

## 11\. Data Retention

Etsy will retain your information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this policy, for as long as your account is active (i.e., for the lifetime of your Etsy member account), or as needed to provide the Services to you. If you no longer want Etsy to use your information to provide the Services to you, you may close your account. Etsy will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your information to comply with applicable tax/revenue laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. In addition, Etsy sellers may also be required to retain and use your information in order to comply with their legal obligations. Please note that closing your account may not free up your email address, username, or shop name (if any) for reuse on a new account. We also retain log files for internal analysis purposes. These log files are generally retained for a brief period of time, except in cases where they are used for site safety and security, to improve site functionality, or we are legally obligated to retain them for longer time periods.

## 12\. Your Rights

If you would like to manage, change, limit, or delete your personal information, you can do so via your Etsy account settings or by contacting us. Upon request, Etsy will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information.  By visiting your account settings, you can access, correct, change, and delete certain personal information associated with your account. In certain cases where we process your information, you may also have a right to restrict or limit the ways in which we use your personal information. In certain circumstances, you also have the right to object to the processing of your personal information, to request the deletion of your personal information, and to obtain a copy of your personal information in an easily accessible format. If you need further assistance, you can contact Etsy through one of the channels listed below under “Contact Etsy.” We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

## 13\. Withdrawing Consent

You have the right to withdraw your consent to our processing of your information and your use of the Services. You can do this at any time by closing your account through your account settings and then emailing legal@etsy.com to request that your personal information be deleted. 

If you withdraw your consent to the use or sharing of your personal information for the purposes set out in this policy, you may not have access to all (or any) of the Services, and we might not be able to provide you all (or any) of the Services. Please note that, in certain cases, we may continue to process your information after you have withdrawn consent and requested that we delete your information, if we have a legal basis to do so. For example, we may retain certain information if we need to do so to comply with an independent legal obligation, or if it is necessary to do so to pursue our legitimate interest in keeping the Services safe and secure. 

## 14\. Privacy Policy Changes

We may amend or update this policy from time to time. If we believe that the changes are material, we’ll let you know by doing one (or more) of the following: (1) posting the changes on or through the Services, (2) sending you an email or message about the changes, or (3) posting an update in the version notes on the Apps’ platform. We will also give you the opportunity to consent to these changes. That way you can decide whether you want to continue using the Services. Changes will be effective upon the posting of the changes and your acceptance of the changes, which may be through your continued use of the Services after the changes take effect.

If you have questions or suggestions about personal information you can contact Etsy’s Support team [via our Help Center](https://www.etsy.com/help/contact), by sending an email to legal@etsy.com, or by writing to us at one of the following addresses:

In North America or South America:  
Etsy Support Team – Privacy Policy  
117 Adams Street  
Brooklyn, NY 11201, USA

Outside of North America or South America:  
Etsy Support Team – Privacy Policy  
66/67 Great Strand Street  
Dublin 1 Ireland

Without prejudice to any other rights you may have, if you reside outside of North America or South America, you also have the right to file a complaint against Etsy with the Irish Data Protection Commissioner, which is Etsy’s Lead Supervisory Authority.

Last updated on Oct 2, 2017
